<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Cormac Quinn</title>
 <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2017-03-28T23:19:03+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://cquinn96.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Cormac Quinn</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>IHG Point Break Hotel Map</title>
   <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io//2017/03/28/ihg-point-break/"/>
   <updated>2017-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://cquinn96.github.io/2017/03/28/ihg-point-break</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Most of you reading this probably know what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ihg.com/rewardsclub/content/gb/en/redeem-rewards/pointbreaks&quot;&gt;IHG point breaks&lt;/a&gt; are, but for those who don&amp;#39;t, it&amp;#39;s when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ihg.com/&quot;&gt;IHG&lt;/a&gt; reduce hotel point redemptions to 5,000 per night in select hotels around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can mean a saving of over 20,000 points on some hotels per night which is amazing! However, I&amp;#39;ve always found it quite tricky to spot the hotels I&amp;#39;m interested in when IHG release the (fairly long) list of hotels every few months. So I decided to create a map of these hotels which will help me, and hopefully some of you, to plan trips. For those interested in the technical details see below the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Icon = Still up for grabs.
Red Icon = Unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=1peKGEbnhcfhgjVR8DvVVC60z-74&quot; width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you click the icon on the top left of the map, you can select/deselect which categories you want to see (Remaining/Sold Out). In that pane you can also view a list of the hotels in each catorgory and click on them to bring you to it&amp;#39;s location. There is also a buttion to view the map full screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try and keep this map updated regularly (more often when a new list has been released).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because a hotel was available in the current Point Break list, doesn&amp;#39;t mean it will be available next time, but it&amp;#39;s a good indication what hotels might show up which is why I have included the unavailable hotels on the map too too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technical details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a Python script to collect the data from IHG, parse it and store it in a suitable format (CSV) to upload to Google Map Maker. The algorithm retreives the set of all hotels originally announced, A, the set of hotels currently available, B, and finds the relative complement of B in A (A \ B) - which is the unavailable hotels set. It then outputs to two CSV files, one containing the available hotels and the other containing the unavailable set. Any time an update is needed to the data, I can run the script again and upload the output files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future improvements include adding the hotel URL to each marker and possibly automating all manual work (although that may be overkill since the data doesnt update that frequently).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I don&amp;#39;t make any money from this website so if you found this map useful feel free to buy me a beer :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.me/CormacQ&quot;&gt;PayPal.me&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://monzo.me/cormacquinn&quot;&gt;Monzo.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Week of Work</title>
   <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io//2014/07/01/first-week-of-work/"/>
   <updated>2014-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://cquinn96.github.io/2014/07/01/first-week-of-work</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I’ve just completed my first working week in China. On our first day, the other interns and I met the CRCC program coordinators early in the morning who escorted us to each of our respective companies that we would be interning with. I didn’t know what to expect, although I’ve done a few different internships before so I wasn’t too nervous this time thankfully. I’m interning with fellow Irishman (the one I met in Dublin airport on the way over) which I think helped too. We met our supervisor, Patricia, who was very friendly and invited us to introduce ourselves to the whole office (we tried in Chinese!). We then sat down at our desks and got an overview of the project and the company itself. Patricia speaks English quite well, but most of the other workers do not, although everyone was very nice and welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Office-1-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-right&quot; title=&quot;My office&quot;&gt;
My first impressions were generally quite positive. The project that I was assigned to looks very interesting, and although the team had already done quite a lot of work on it, there was still some way to go until it would be finished. It’s a web based tablet application that handles factory inspections for a large inspection company in Asia. I was excited to set up my development environment and get stuck into the development, but first I needed to read the documentation and understand the fairly complex system which took up most of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our first day we were brought to McDonalds for lunch which I was a bit surprised by; If a Chinese person was visiting Ireland for the first time I don’t think the first place I would bring them is a McDonalds or an authentic Chinese restaurant – they could get that in China! I would have them eating an Irish fry up or some homemade Irish Stew. &lt;img src=&quot;/images/Lunch-at-Work-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-left&quot; title=&quot;Lunch at work&quot;&gt; On the second day our coworkers invited us to have lunch with them in the canteen so of course I said yes, jumping at the opportunity to have some authentic Chinese food. Unfortunately it was bland, and overall wasn’t anything to get excited about. I really struggled to get the fishbones out with just chopsticks too. Our coworkers told us that this was just cheap plain food, and even they don’t really like it themselves so it made me more hopefull for future meals. I quickly noticed that they didn’t sell water in the canteen. It’s apparently bad for your stomach to mix so much boiled rice with water… who knew? I’ll have to trust the Chinese on that one. By day 4 I was dreaming of that McDonalds again, and on day 5 the other intern and I caved and went and got a cheeseburger meal. I felt ashamed, and so I said I would go on the hunt for a good Chinese restaurant nearby next week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I didn’t know about before joining my company is that they allow just over 2 hours for lunch, which was completely new to me as I was used to 30-45 minutes or so back home. The reason they get so long is that most of the workers take a nap at their desks straight after eating... the first time I came back after lunch and seen the lights off, I was slightly confused. I haven’t joined them in napping yet, but there’s still time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve organised a trip to XiChong beach for this weekend with a few other interns, and I’m really looking forward to it. I’ve seen pictures and heard about the overcrowding at Chinese beaches which is why I choose a beach far outside the city, hopefully it pays off…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Induction Day and First Weekend in China</title>
   <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io//2014/06/28/induction-day-first-weekend/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://cquinn96.github.io/2014/06/28/induction-day-first-weekend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I managed to get up on time for the CRCC induction day… although I don’t know how with the massive time difference and my lack of sleep. We were taxied to a hotel in downtown Shenzhen, where we had our first Chinese breakfast. I can’t say that I overly enjoyed it, but I was too hungry to care. It consisted of dumplings and noodles along with hot water to wash it down. Oh and of course chopsticks. Now, don’t get me wrong, I’m a big fan of noodles but for breakfast it wouldn’t be my first choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Business-Card-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-right&quot; title=&quot;My business card&quot;&gt;
This was the first time I had tried dumplings though and they were very good. We barely had time to finish before we were whisked upstairs and were formally introduced to the CRCC Asia team. They all were very friendly and seemed really helpful. We introduced ourselves one by one (there was about 30 interns) and were given our Chinese business cards. We were then taught how to give/receive them in China (you give your card with 2 hands with the card facing up, and when you are receiving, you accept the card with 2 hands again and you don’t put it away straight away; you should read it, and ask questions based on it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also taught the meaning of guanxi (关系), which is a Chinese concept. It loosely translates to relationships or connections, but it means so much more in Chinese culture, especially in the Chinese world of business, which we learnt, is built on guanxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Chinese-English-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-left&quot; title=&quot;Chinese-English; A sign in the lift of my apartment.&quot;&gt;
Another concept we learned was miànzi (面子), which is the Chinese idea of ‘face’. Say for example, you got angry and started shouting on the street you would lose face, or conversely if you paid for everyone’s meal you would gain face. Another way of putting it is that miànzi represents social perceptions of a person’s prestige. I think this is a great concept that I feel isn’t used enough in Western culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then taught some beginner Mandarin phrases to help us get by until Monday (our first full Chinese lesson), which I really enjoyed. I learnt how to say 1-99 and a couple of other phrases. You might think, learning 1-99 is a lot for a 30 minute beginner lesson but not with Chinese. Once you can say 1-9 you can reuse these numbers to form any number up to 99. So for 56 you would say wǔ (5) shí (10) liù (6). Simple. Then once you know the word for 100 you can say up to 999 and so on. I think this is an excellent numbering system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/All-of-the-interns-300x225.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-right&quot; title=&quot;Our intern group&quot;&gt;
That evening we had our official welcome dinner, which consisted of… food, I think. I still wasn’t used to the dishes coming out one by one, and we would demolish one plate of some kind of meat or vegetables and have to wait fine minutes for the next. But we ordered a couple of beers and got to know each other better. After the meal, we went out to the bar/nightclub part of the city. It was quite different from what I was expecting, it was very western (we went to the western bar and club area of Shenzhen known as Coco Park). We split up as no one really knew where to go or how to keep in touch with everyone so our group went to the Irish bar, McCawley’s. I was excited when I seen where we were going, but in the end was a bit disappointed by the bar. Firstly I was the only Irish person in sight (in a city of 13 million people I was a bit surprised), but then I found out why; A pint was roughly £5.50... which for back home is bad enough but for China, it&amp;#39;s crazy expensiv . But we stayed for a few, and had ended up having a great night out. I slept until about 3pm the next day (I’m going to blame the jet-lag for this, not the alcohol) and when I got up, found out that the plan was to go to a pool in the Venice Hotel, which is a very swanky hotel in the middle of Shenzhen. We got there expecting to pay an entrance fee but there didn’t seem to be one and the staff didn’t mention anything, and we had the huge pool all to ourselves. Fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day a group of us decided to go to Shenzhen zoo. It wasn&amp;#39;t cheap (£20 per person), but I made the most out of it… I had a snake around my neck, I rode an elephant and fed crocodiles some meat. We also got a chance to go out in the lake. The most disappointing thing though, was that one of the lions looked severely malnourished. To the point where I couldn’t believe that they would let this happen in a zoo and so we just left soon after. We got taxi’s back to the apartment and I slept like a baby as soon as I got in the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that was my first weekend in China, so far so good. I start work on tomorrow (Monday) morning so I’ll be sure to make a post about my first week working here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Moving to China</title>
   <link href="http://cquinn96.github.io//2014/06/26/moving-to-china/"/>
   <updated>2014-06-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://cquinn96.github.io/2014/06/26/moving-to-china</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi there! As a bit of background to this post, I was offered 2 internships for this summer. One was based in the USA and the other was in China. Now this was an extremely tough decision for me to have to decide between the two. I’ve always wanted to visit/live in the US and now I was offered a paid internship, with accommodation and flights included. I had never even thought about living in China before, but having this offer for an internship really piqued my interest. After doing some more research and a lot of deliberating (ask my girlfriend, she’ll certainly tell you) I settled on China. Why? I don’t have a definitive answer. But the company that I will be interning with, seemed to have quite a good reputation in the IT sector. I also thought that I would, more than likely, never have the chance to live in China so easily again in my life, so I thought why not? I got started on some beginner Mandarin lessons right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months later and I finished my placement year in Belfast, and the time had come to leave for China. &lt;img src=&quot;/images/Me-at-Dublin-Airport-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-right&quot; title=&quot;Me at Dublin airport&quot;&gt; I had bought everything I needed and researched where I was going countless times but I still couldn’t believe it was happening, right up to the night before I was due to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internship program is run by CRCC Asia. Normally students have to pay to get onto the program, which includes accommodation, business seminars, cultural events and more, but I was awarded a fully funded scholarship by the government. The internship lasts 2 months and is based in Shenzhen, China. On top of this, CRCC Asia offered me the chance to take part in The Dragon Trip, which is a 20 day trip around China and includes stops at cities like Xi’an to see the Terracotta Warriors and Beijing to camp out on the Great Wall of China for a night and much more… so I of course jumped at the opportunity. It cost me a fair amount, but I didn’t know when I would have the chance to do something like this again. Also we are going to see pandas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew with Emirates from Dublin to Hong Kong, with a 3 hour layover in Dubai which broke up the journey nicely. The flight took about 20 hours. In Dublin airport, I met a fellow student who was on the intenrship and met a few more when we landed in Hong Kong Airport who were also flying in from all over the world. Several of us then took the ferry from Hong Kong airport to Shekou ferry terminal in Shenzhen where we met our program coordinators, which took about 1 hour and then we all crammed into a mini van and made our way to our apartments. All in all, the total journey time was roughly 24 hours. I slept for about 3 hours of that, so I was very, very tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Apartment-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-left&quot; title=&quot;My apartment&quot;&gt;
We arrived at the apartment at about 6pm and were told that we would have an informal dinner at 7. Most of us hurried up to our rooms and had a quick shower before meeting back in the lobby at 6.45. Still exhausted but excited, I went for my first Chinese meal. We walked to a nearby shopping mall and had a table waiting for us. The food was strange, but nice. This probably wasn’t the best time for me to start learning how to use chopsticks, although I had no choice otherwise I wasn’t going to be eating! It’s Chinese custom for one person, usually the most senior, to order food for everyone and it will be placed in the middle of the table and shared (everyone uses chopsticks to fill their own plates). &lt;img src=&quot;/images/First-Meal-300x168.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;float-right&quot; title=&quot;First meal in China&quot;&gt; Something which I found even more peculiar was that the noodles and rice are served last, once you’ve finished eating the meat and veg. I asked about this and the reason is because restaurants want to give you the best food first, and they consider rice and noodles ‘filler food’. What’s Chinese for ‘bring everything out all at once please’?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the meal we all went back to our apartments. I got into bed almost immediately as I was still completely exhausted from the journey and I had to be up at 7am to go to our induction the following day. I still could hardly believe that I was in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, heres to 3 months of adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
